Mss.B.L493
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 7.0 Linear feet 17 upright boxes, 1 oversized folder, 1 digital record. (Box 1-17)
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte, Philadelphia, undated; 8x5; Maclean, John
    Washington. A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers Will do all he can to help him in the advancement of science. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [J.L. ?] Le Conte, undated; 5 1/4" x 8"; Matthews, A. (Andrew), 1815-1897
    n.d. A.L.S. 3p. Pencil notes by J.L. Le Conte.
  - Letter to [J.L.] Le Conte, undated; 4 1/2" x 7"; Matthews, A. (Andrew), 1815-1897
    n.d. A.L.S. 6p.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], undated; 4 1/2" x 7"; Matthews, A. (Andrew), 1815-1897
    n.d. A.L.S. 4p.
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, undated; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Ménétries, E. (Édouard), 1802-1861
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. in French. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte, undated; 7x4-1/2; Mitchell, S. Weir, (Silas Weir), 1829-1914
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Invitation to a meeting. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte]., undated; 8x5; Motschulsky, Victor de
    A.L.S. 3p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) American coleoptera. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Jo[h]n L. Leconte., undated; 8x5; Patterson, Robert, 1819-1909
    A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Asks if he will discuss entomology with a friend at the Academy of Natural Sciences.
  - Concerning his claims to the invention of the gasoline engine., undated; Quabach, William H.
    A.D.S. 13p.of writing and sketches. Various sizes. (see Le Conte papers.)
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, undated; 5" x 8"; Rogers, Fairman, 1833-1900
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte., undated; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Rogers, W. H.
    A.L.S. 2p. Incomplete. (see Le Conte papers.) Entomology. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte]., undated; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Saussure, Henri de, 1829-1905
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Sent him a publication through Baird.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte]., undated; 8x5-1/4; Saussure, Henri de, 1829-1905
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Informs him the plants will be sent and tells him of the cost.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte., undated; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Saussure, Henri de, 1829-1905
    A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) Forwards insects. Concerning his works on insects.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte]., undated; 8x5-1/4; Saussure, Henri de, 1829-1905
    A.L.S. 1p. In French. (see Le Conte papers.) His visit in America. Refers to Harris and Lea. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte]., undated; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Say, Lucy Way Sistaire, 1801-1886
    A.L.S. 4p. Incomplete. (see Le Conte papers.) Friendly letter. Never visits Philadelphia. Place of residence.
  - Letter to [J.L. Le Conte], undated; 5 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Schaupp, F. G.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], undated; 5" x 8"; Schaupp, F. G.
    Brooklyn n.d. A.L.S. 3p.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte], undated; 8x5; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte papers Will be happy to help him get the post [of commissioner of agriculture?]. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to Helen [G. Le Conte], undated; 6 1/2" x 8"; Stevens, Matilda Jane Harden
  - Letter to J[ohn] L. Le Conte., undated; 8x5; Tellkampf, Theodor
    A.L.S. 3p. (see Le Conte papers) Concerning his article on entomology.
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte., undated; 8x5; Thomson, James
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers) Hopes to see him before sailing for Paris.
  - Letter to [John L. Le Conte?], undated; 10-1/4x8; Walsh, B. D. (Benjamin Dann), 1808-1869
    A.L.S. 2p. Incomplete. (see Le Conte papers.) Describes an insect which is spreading eastward and asks for information as to the date of their appearance.
  - List of insects., undated; 12-1/2x8; Walsh, B. D. (Benjamin Dann), 1808-1869
  - Letter to [John L.] Le Conte., undated; 6-1/4x4; Wilson, T. B.
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Le Conte papers.) Asks that he acknowledge a gift of fossils to the Academy. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to John L. Le Conte, undated; 10x8; Woodhouse, S. W. (Samuel Washington), 1821-1904
    Philadelphia. A.L.S. 2p. (see Le Conte paper Describes cave with Indian hieroglyphs Natural history. His comments on an exploring expedition. Originally B L493.2
  - Letter to [Helen Grier LeConte], undated
  - Letter to [John L. LeConte?], undated
  - List of Dr. Harris' Donaciae, undated
  - List of entomological specimens, undated
  - List of managers of the Franklin Institute, undated
  - Report on West Point, undated
  - Unidentified surveyor's exercise, undated; 1 map, 53.9 x 33 cm
    Contains such notes as: "Beginning at a Small rock and Black Oak," "Iron bolt in a rock where a mark'd red oak stood opposite the old Mill," "marked hickory near the side of the creek," etc., with the "Turn Pike" and the stream clearly marked.
    Other Finding Aids note
    Realms of Gold, 24 (1).
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    Oversized.
- Family Papers, 1827-1901; 0.25 Linear feet 1 half-size upright box. (Box 18)
  - Letter to Louis LeConte, 1827 November 29; LeConte, John Eatton, 1784-1860
    General note
    Personal letter. A.L.S.
  - Letter to Louis LeConte, 1830 February 25; LeConte, John Eatton, 1784-1860
    Genral note
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda J. Harden Stevens, 1856 September 10; LeConte, John Eatton, 1784-1860
  - Envelope addressed to Mrs. Matilda J. Harden Stevens, 1859 January 18; LeConte, John L., (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
    Envelope only
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda J. Harden Stevens, 1859 April 28; LeConte, John L., (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
  - Letter to Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1859 July 9; LeConte, John Eatton, 1784-1860
  - Letter to Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1859 July 31; LeConte, John Eatton, 1784-1860
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1859 August 28; LeConte, John Eatton, 1784-1860
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda J. Harden Stevens, 1859 October 15; LeConte, John L., (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1859 October 23; LeConte, John Eatton, 1784-1860
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1860 February 12; LeConte, John Eatton, 1784-1860
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Matilda J[ane] Harden [Stevens], 1860 November 21; LeConte, Joseph, 1823-1901
  - Letter to Ann LeConte Stevens, 1860 December 15; LeConte, John L., (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1860 December 26; LeConte, John L., (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1861 [April] 18; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1863 January 29; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1864 September 30; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda J. Harden Sumner Stevens, 1865 June 1; LeConte, John L., (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Sumner Stevens, 1866 November 8; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1869 February 21; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. T. Sumner Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1876 May 4; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. T. S. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1876 June 25; Harden, Jane LeConte
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda J. Harden Sumner Stevens, 1876 October 30; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. T. Sumner Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1876 December 17; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda J. Harden Stevens, 1877 December 31; LeConte, John L., (John Lawrence), 1825-1883
  - Letter to Mrs. T. Sumner Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1878 April 25; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. T. Sumner Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1878 December 11; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. T. Sumner Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1879 January 18; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. T. Sumner Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1879 March 24; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1884 April 3; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. T. S. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1889 June 23; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. T. Sumner Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1889 September 20; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. T. Sumner Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1891 March 16; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. T. Sumner Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1891 May 11; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. T. Sumner Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1893 December 23; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Golden wedding [anniversary] card, 1897 January 14; LeConte, Joseph L.
    anniversary card
  - Newspaper clippings on various LeConte family members in San Francisco Call, Atlanta Constitution and other newspapers, 1897 February 19
    Photocopies of newspaper clippings about various members of the LeConte family.
    LeConte family.
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1897 September 27; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Master Sumner Morrison Ramsey, 1899 February 17; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1899 July 27; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1900 June 6; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1900 November 3; LeConte, Joseph L.
  - Letter to Mrs. Matilda Jane Harden Stevens, 1901 January 23; LeConte, Joseph L.
- Bound Volumes, 0.5 Linear feet 1 upright box. (Box 19)
  - Meleagris Gallopavo, undated (Box 19)
    Handwritten materials, sketches, printed clipping.
  - Account book, Jan. 1823 - May 1840 (Box 19)
    A monthly list of expenses, primarily food (fish, eggs, coffee, butcher, etc.)
  - Cheiroptera, undated (Box 19)
    Handwritten notes, sketches.
  - Dissection of Salamander, undated
    Handwritten notes and sketches.
  - Extrait des Statuts de la Société Entomologique de Russie, confirmés par SA MAJESTÉ L'EMPEREUR de toutes les Russies, Dec. 4, 1859
  - American Cheiroptera, undated
    Handwritten notes, loose notes.
    August 15, 1863 letter from James D. Dana placed with correspondence along with insect sketch (see Series I). "New Coleoptera and Localities, commencing May, 1857" foldered separately within this series.
  - New Coleoptera and Localities, commencing May, 1857
    Originally tucked into "American Cheiroptera" notebook.
  - Salem Quarterly Meeting of Ministers and Elders, Feb. 13, 1828 - Nov. 15, 1837
  - Henry B. Chew and James M. Mason vs. Benjamin Chew, Mar. Term 1855
    "Supplemental paper book of defendant in answer to plaintiffs' paper book"
  - George W. Edwards vs. James G. Edwards et al, Jan. Term 1858
    Supreme Court for the Eastern District of Pennsylvania
  - Vespertilionidae, undated
    Handwritten notes.
  - Soricinae, undated
  - Geometry, undated
    Handwritten notes and mathematical diagrams.
  - Rodentia, Oct. 1853, ?
    Removed "Rubus" and "Zoological Notes from 1808 to 1816" notebooks.
    Handwritten notes and sketches, published article on Arvicolae.
  - Rubus, undated
    Found tucked into "Rodentia" notebook.
  - Zoological Notes from 1808 to 1816, 1808-1816
    Originally tucked into "Rodentia" notebook.
  - Notebooks on Various Subjects, undated
    Subject matter includes cylinders and spheres, zoology, manuals, entomology, etc. Written in part by John L. LeConte.